The closer the entrance is to the palace,
the closer the exit will be
to the throne room over here.
Well, okay. Then we're all in agreement.
We'll charge in as close as we can
from the exit by the central staircase.
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
Nobody told me the stronger the ability,
the bigger my stomach would get.
This was a mistake.
For a girl, there's nothing worse
than losing your figure.
I should go and ask Sir Leol
for a larger reward.
Right, Shidore?
[Hina] I keep her around
'cause she's a rare peon
that understands speech, but…
Come on. Can't you at least participate
in the conversation?
She's a foreigner.
She can't blend in
with the other citizens.
What? Is one escaped woman
really that important?
[whimpers]
[chuckles]
I can go find her for you.
The Royal Guard appreciates your work,
and I respect you too.
This could benefit both of us,
so what do you say we work together?
Excellent point.
You wait here while I go find something.
If he took his shoes off
and left them here
to avoid leaving footprints,
That was the day Taragette went missing.
If I had to bet,
I'd say that intruder killed him.
But that would mean that
after he left his shoes behind,
he disposed of Taragette's body.
No. I'll just catch the intruder myself.
I see.
The tracks lead deeper inside the palace.
This trumps Bizeff's woman.
Now, follow me!
I asked his name, but he didn't tell me.
[wind blowing]
[King] Well, who am I?
A nameless king in a borrowed castle.
I fear nothing
except the tedium that it will bring!
[giggles] And with that,
he's beaten all of us.
Then it's up to you to tell him that.
There is no way I'm gonna get hit again.
[Neferpitou] How does this
sound to you, sire?
We can block all the aura
in the vicinity surrounding you.
It is my fervent hope
that it would prevent
my mere presence from bothering you.
[King] You suggest
that I stay in one place?
Or could you simply move the area?
Could its location change
as I moved around freely?
Is it possible?
I refuse to have my movement
constantly monitored.
No. We would never propose to you
something so restrictive.
[King] So if I do not wish
to endure your presence,
I will only be able to move
within that confined area?
Then if it were my wish to go elsewhere,
you would have to move it. Is that right?
at least until tomorrow's sorting.
That will suffice.
It's not enough?
that your En is as worthless
as a common sieve. Am I wrong?
would limit its benefits.
I would miss any attacks
coming from underground.
[King] Are you referring to Komugi, then?
No. I am referring to the 11 soldiers
who still remain stationed
within the palace.
They have all been allowed the freedom
to come and go from here as they see fit,
with minimal supervision.
And of course we check thoroughly
every time one of them enters,
but if a soldier were to be
somehow controlled by the enemy,
it would be difficult at best
to know for sure. Also--
You will not come unless summoned,
so disturb me at your own peril.
on or above the second floor anyway.
If intruders come up from underground,
you will be in a good position
to deal with them.
Still, the King's been
in a real bad mood lately.
would be more than enough
to remove all doubt.
However, that would be
a grave insult to the King.
No, I'm only making excuses.
Whatever is growing within him
is causing me
unbearable anxiety and dread.
I can't bear it.
[Welfin] Damn. Looks like
the rain washed away the trail,
but now I have the answer.
The intruder hid here
to check the second floor,
but instead of going upstairs,
he left the palace.
the King will definitely kill you.
Go and let everyone else know that too.
Sir!
Wings. What if the intruder
has the ability to fly?
The shoes and the scent
may have been a diversion.
It's possible that he flew up
to the second floor.
-Sir Youpi.
-Hmm?
Oh, uh…
Pitou is monitoring the palace with En.
If they'd made it up to the second floor,
they would have been caught.
-[chuckles] No. Sorry. It was nothing.
-Hmm?
[Welfin] But that doesn't make sense.
How did the intruder reach the stairway?
Sir Youpi…
[Menthuthuyoupi] Yeah? What is it?
Has there ever been a time
that Sir Pitou stopped using En?
I mean, what about that day last week
when it rained?
Wait. What?
You didn't hear about what happened?
There was a massive panic right after
the King tore off his own left arm.
Huh?
Pouf was in charge of En
while Pitou was responsible
for healing him.
[Welfin] And how wide is Pouf's En,
if you don't mind me asking?
And how the hell would I know that?
As wide as Pitou's?
It all makes sense.
The question now is
what the intruder's objective was
and whether he's still
hiding around here somewhere.
[yawns]
[Welfin] I should report to Pitou or Pouf.
Pouf would be best.
And, if possible, I need to determine
exactly what the intruder's objective was.
Otherwise, my report would be
that the intruder
somehow made it inside the palace,
I guess I can make up an objective,
but if the intruder is captured,
they'll find out I lied for sure.
But then if I tell the Royal Guard
about my suspicion
I have an idea.
So the intruder captured one of my men.
Leol tells me
that this intruder is able to teleport.
He may be working with your woman,
and they might have
teleported out together.
But I was able to discern their objective.
And?
They planned to blow up the palace.
Yeah, right.
[gasps] We must tell the Royal Guard!
-No.
-Huh?
What's the rush? We can tell them
right after you and I find the bomb.
But there's no time!
Just calm down
and think about it from their perspective.
If they want to blow up the palace,
then they'll wait until the King's here.
And when's that?
When all the citizens have been assembled,
before the ceremony begins.
It'll be a sight to behold.
It's safe to assume that
the enemy's reached the same conclusion.
[Bizeff] True.
The Royal Guard
should know that we're serious.
If we save the King's life,
they're bound to be grateful to us.
Right?
Yes, that's… that's true.
As soon as I find the bomb,
I'll contact you.
Yes, that's perfect.
[Welfin scoffs]
Hold on. About your ability…
and then I'll tap you
when I start to hold my breath again,
so don't you forget.
[laughs] Fine,
but there's no need to push your limits.
Give yourself all the buffer you need.
Just leave things to me
whenever God's Accomplice isn't active.
And you can trust me.
I know what I'm doing here. Hmm?
Tracking the smell of cigarette smoke
is really easy for them.
We could all be knocked out
the same second I take my first breath.
The boss will put up a smoke screen
when we go in. It'll be fine.
You may be right, but I still want
to eliminate as much risk as possible.
I don't want to do anything
I might regret.
and were discussing something.
Pitou stayed,
while Youpi went back inside.
As for Pouf, he returned to the air,
so I don't think anything has changed.
I'll let you know
if anything else happens.
[Gon] Oh.
So I guess he still has his doubts.
Well, I can pretty much guarantee
that they'll be near the King.
Hey, you don't know that.
We have to be ready for anything.
We don't wanna be caught off guard
if something happens.
[Ikalgo] If you knew how loyal they were,
you wouldn't say that.
I'm telling you there's no way
they'd ever leave the King.
The Royal Guard is always right there
by his side. You can count on it.
-[Ikalgo] Exceptions? Like what?
-[Killua] There are all kinds of things…
so maybe he's been making babies.
Yeah, I guess.
I hadn't thought of that,
but I guess it would give the King
a good reason to keep the Royal Guard
far away from his chamber.
You think what Bizeff was doing
[Knuckle] Glad we thought of this
before we set out.
[Shoot] If we hadn't been bracing for it,
we would have been
completely caught off guard.
Do you get it now?
I'm telling you,
you can never overthink something.
And there are lots of other things
we haven't even thought of yet.
[scoffs]
[Killua] Yeah,
something's still bothering me.
Right.
[Killua] It bothers me, but the existence
of a third party, woman or not,
is a good thing to consider.
Hold on a second.
I thought that was just a theory
you were thinking about.
Yeah, but you agreed that
there was no other logical explanation.
You realize you're contradicting yourself.
Didn't you just get through telling us
that there could be other exceptions?
Following that logic,
Yeah.
Right. Just think about it.
Why would anyone want to hurt themselves?
For what reason?
That does make sense.
That would mean we're not dealing
with an unemotional despot here,
He's willing to endure searing pain
for the sake of his pride.
People like him
will never be willing to compromise.
I know that much from my own experience.
If the King won't budge,
then neither will his Guards,
so count on combat being our only option.
[Killua] Morel summed everything up nicely
but he's wrong.
The King's self-harm,
the existence of a third party…
We're still nowhere close to figuring out
what really happened.
I've got a feeling
that whatever the answer is,
it has the potential
to completely screw up our entire plan.
[Morel] It's time.
One minute left to go.
Gather round.
[Killua] Damn. We're out of time.
[exhales]
Here we go.
-Get ready to rumble!
-[closing theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[upbeat music playing]
[Gon] Next time, Charge and Invade.
Nothing beats having a hot pot in winter.
[Killua] Reminds me of mystery pots.
[Gon] Charge into the pot!